Guide to the Majority Report Research Files TAM.548
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Majority Report Research Files
1969-1979
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Majority Report (New York, N.Y.)
TAM.548
4.75 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes and 2 flat boxes.
Majority Report (1971-1979) was a New York based feminist newspaper published by an editorial collective and dedicated to the women's liberation movement. Majority Report's research files dated 1969-1979 are on feminists, popular, political and literary figures, movement activism and events related to women's rights issues. The files contain clippings from various feminist and mainstream publications, select issues of publications including the Majority Report, correspondence, press releases, writings, notes, printed ephemera and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials. Materials appear to have been transferred from Barnard College's Wollman Library in 2010. The accession number associated with this collection in 2010.065.
Historical Note
Majority Report was a feminist newspaper published in New York City from 1971-1979. Although the oft-named editor of the paper is Nancy Borman, the paper was published through an editorial collective, with Borman guiding the paper from its establishment. For the majority of its run, Majority Report was published biweekly, its circulation is recorded as being from 11,000 to 20,000.Majority Report was initially launched by the Women's Strike Coalition, a New York based women's rights activist group, but subsequent issues were published through the group Feminist Organization for Communication Action and Service (FOCAS). As a "collective newsletter" seeking to unify women's liberation groups and to alleviate the costs of an independent publication, Majority Report had a unique editorial policy: it published together and without edits, the individual newsletters of various women's liberation groups across the leftist political spectrum - liberal, progressive, and radical alike. Majority Report was also known for its monthly calendar of feminist events, its directory of feminist businesses, and the feminist advertisements it ran. Noted contributors to the publication include Gay-Women's Liberation Front (G-WLF) and the National Organization for Women (NOW).
Sources:
Lueck, Therese L. "Majority Report." Women's Periodicals in the United States: Social and Political Issues, edited by Kathleen L. Endres and Therese L. Lueck, 1996, pp. 195-200.
Editor of 'Majority Report' to Speak at WWC. The Kingston Daily Freeman, 7 August 1975, p. 15. (Kingston, NY.)
Scope and Content Note
Majority Report's Research Files dated 1969-1979 contain the publication's research material related to the women's liberation movement. The research files contain biographical information on feminists, and other popular, political, and literary figures. The files document feminist political activism, women's campaigns for political office, women's rights issues, and events concerning the movement. There is a substantial file on Bella Abzug and Patty Hearst, as well as Katherine Ann Power, Susan Saxe, and the FBI's investigation into the women's liberation movement. The bulk of the collection consists of clippings, press releases, writings and print ephemera from various feminist and mainstream publications and organizations, as well as select issues of publications including Majority Report. The collection also contains correspondence, much of it addressed to the Majority Report editor. The research files also contain significant number of photographic material of feminist activists, and other public and political figures.
Arrangement
Materials are in the order in which they were found, with minimal physical rearrangement. Oversize materials were separated out and put into flat boxes. The container list is based on an inventory from 2010, with some revisions. The list is in alphabetical order; files on individuals are listed alphabetically by last name.
Feminism -- United States -- Newspapers.; Clippings (information artifacts); Printed ephemera.; Photographic prints.; Feminism -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Women's rights -- United States -- 20th century; Newsletters.; Majority Report (New York, N.Y.)
- Abzug, Bella - articles, statement, news releases, photos, campaign material, 1972-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 4-6, Box 3, Folder 33, Box 8, Folder 4)
- Agnew, Spiro - photo reprint, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Allende, Laura - article, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Anthony, Susan B. - article, photos, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Anthony, Susan B., House - articles, photos, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 48, Box 7, Folder 8)
- Armstrong, Anne - article, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Arthur, Beatrice - photo (news reprint), undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Assorted Clippings, 1975-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 41, Box 7, Folder 9)
- Assorted Photographs, 1970's (Box 6, Folder 4-5, 7-12)
- Atkins, Susan - article, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Atkinson, Ti-Grace - photos, statement, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Baird, Bill - letter article, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Baldwin, Faith - articles, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 21, Box 7, Folder 6)
- Balis, Andrea - photos, letter, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Barrett, Edith - article, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Barrett, Rona - article, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Bayh, Birch (Senator) - photos, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Beach, Amy Cheney - article, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Beame, Abraham - articles, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 23, Box 7, Folder 6)
- Beauvoir, Simone de - notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Becker, Natalie - vitae, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Bellamy, Carol - photos, undated (Box 3, Folder 15 and 30)
- Bernard, Dr. Jessie - photo, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Bio - press release, clippings, 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 9, Box 7, Folder 7)
- Biographies: Women in the News - articles, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 3, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Biography File: articles, photos, press releases, 1974-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 39-40, Box 7, Folder 10-11)
- Blumenthal, Albert - campaign promo, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Boggs, Lindy - article, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bonney, Therese (Mabel) - article, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Bottini, Ivy - articles, photo, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Brady, Anne, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Breast Prosthesis, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Brophy, Brigid, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Brooks, Gwendolyn, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Brown, Hester, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Brown, Rosemary, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Brownmiller, Susan, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Bryant, Anita - article, notes, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10, Box 8, Folder 4)
- Busch, Werner - paper, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Carter, Jimmy articles, 1975-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 11-13, 31, Box 3, Folder 31, Box 7, Folder 6, Box 8, Folder 3, 8-9)
- Cave, Jennie - article, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Ceballos, Jacqui - news release, statements, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Chambers, Marilyn - article, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Chisholm, Shirley, 1969-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 17, Box 3, Folder 32, Box 8, Folder 5)
- Christian, Meg - articles, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Clark, Ramsey - news release, letter campaign stuff, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- CLIT/Solanas, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Colette - article, 1973, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Cook, Constance - articles, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Corbin, Margaret - articles, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21, Box 8, Folder 3)
- Court, Margaret - photo, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Crimmins, Alice - articles, photo, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 22, Box 8, Folder 3)
- Cunningham, Anne - article, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Curtis, Charlotte - photo, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Davidson, Joan, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Davis, Angela - photo, articles, 1972-1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 20, Box 6, Folder 6)
- Davis, Elizabeth Gould - notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Day, Doris - article, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Day, Dorothy - leaflet, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- DeCrow, Karen - resumes, articles, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5, Box 8, Folder 2)
- De Saram, Carole, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Deadly Nightshade - photo, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Dembitz, Nanette - article, letter, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Devlin, Bernadette - photo, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dewhurst, Coleen - article, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Dickinson, Emily - article, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Didion, Joan, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Dillon, Tom (Reactionary Democrat), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Dodson, Betty (photo only), undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Duncan, Isadora (photo only), undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Elliot, Cass, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Ervin, Sam, 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 27, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Evert, Chris (photo only), undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Fletcher, Louise (actress), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 29, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Fonda, Jane, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Ford, Gerald and Betty, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Friedan, Betty, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 51, Box 7, Folder 2)
- Friedlander, Miriam, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Fromme, Lynette "Squeaky", 1975 (Box 4, Folder 53, Box 7, Folder 2)
- Furness, Betty, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Garcia, Inez, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 2, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Gillan,Sister Ann (photo only), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Gioseffi, Danielle (photo only), undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Goldman, Emma (photo only), undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Goolagong, Evonne (photo only), undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Gottlieb, Stephen, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Gottlieb, Wilma, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Grad, Judith, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Graham, Ross, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Grand Jury, 1969-1977 (Box 5, Folder 38, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Grasso, Ella, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 10, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Greer, Germaine, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Greitzer, Carol, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Gressey, Loretta, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Guggenheimer, Elinor, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 15, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Gunning, Rosemary (legislator), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Harris, Emily and Bill, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 18, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Harris, Kathryn (photo only), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Harris, Ladonna - photos, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Hayward, Carter - photo, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Hearst, Patty - Trial, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 41, Box 7, Folder 2)
- Hearst, Patty - articles, 1975-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 9, Box 2, Folder 7, Box 8, Folder 2, 6-7)
- Heide, Wilma Scott, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Helms, Richard, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Henie, Sonia, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Henle, Faye, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Hepburn, Katherine, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Hilderly, Jeriann (photo only), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Hills, Carla, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Hirsch, Lolly and Jean, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Holtzman, Liz, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 48, Box 7, Folder 2)
- Horta, Maria Teresa, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Hulett, Josephine, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Hunt, Dorothy, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Isis, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Javits, Marion, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Jerome, Jennie, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Johnson, Jill (photo only), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Jones, Hortense P., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Jones, Nellie, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Kalcheim, Kay, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Kaye, Aaron, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Keller, Helen, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Kennedy, Flo, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Kennedy, Rev. Magora E., S.V.A., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6, Box 7, Folder 5)
- Kimura, Mashiko (sculptress), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- King, Billie Jean, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Kirsten, Dorothy, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Kissinger, Nancy/Henry, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Knauer, Virginia (photo only), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Koch, Edward I - U.S. Rep 17th Congressional District, Manhattan, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Koons, Leonore, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Kopper, Roberta, speechwriter, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Kramarsky, Werner H., undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Krupsak, Mary Anne - Governor's campaign, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 54, Box 7, Folder 4)
- Langley, Jane Pickens - article, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Lebron, Lolita - article, releases, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 7, Box 7, Folder 6)
- Lee, Fran - article, photo, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8, Box 7, Folder 6)
- Liebman, Jan - press release, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Lindfors, Viveca - photos, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Lindsay, John - photos, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Little, Joan - articles, newsletter, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2, Box 7, Folder 6)
- Loos, Anita, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Luce, Clare Booth - articles, press releases, photos, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- MacLaine, Shirley - photo, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Maier, Mary Ann - article, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Mailer, Norman - articles, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Mandel, Barbara "Bootsie" - press releases, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Manley, Joan - articles, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Marchi, John - article, platform, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Marx, Jenny (wife of Karl) - articles, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Massage Parlors, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- McCalla, Deidre - promo piece, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- McCarthy, Abigail - article, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- McCarthy, Mary - photo, news release, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- McQuillan, Pat - articles, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Meir, Golda - photo, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Mellon, Karen Boyd - article, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous - Photographs, Artwork, Clippings, Releases, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous - parts of a lesbian publication, undated (Box 2, Folder 11, Box 8, Folder 1)
- Mitchell, Martha - articles, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 27, Box 8, Folder 3)
- Mondale - Walter and Joan - article, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Monroe, Marilyn - articles, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Moore, Sara - articles, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30, Box 8, Folder 3)
- Morgan, Julia (photo only of her work), undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Morgan, Robin, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Murphy, Sister Maureen, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Murray, Dr. Margaret, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Near, Holly (photo only), undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Nelson, Portia, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- New Haven Women's Liberation Rock Band, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Nixon [Eisenhower], Julia and Pat, 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 47, Box 7, Folder 6)
- Noble, Elaine, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 42, Box 7, Folder 6)
- Norton, Eleanor Holmes, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Oates, Joyce Carol, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Ohrenstein, Manfred, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Ojiambo, Dr. Julia, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- O'Leary, Jean (photo only), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- O'Neill, Nena and George, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Parks, Rosa, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Paul, Alice, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 35, Box 7, Folder 6)
- Percy, Charles, senator (photo only), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Peron, Isabelle, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Plath, Sylvia, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Pogrebin, Letty Cottin, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Victoria, Queen of Britain - photo (reprint), undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Quinlan, Karen Ann, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Rankin, Jeanette, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 33, Box 7, Folder 3)
- Ray, Dixie Lee, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Reddy, Helen, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Red Wing (Lillian St. Cyr), undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Reed, Evelyn, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Reid, Elizabeth - Australian feminist, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Richmond, Fred - articles, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Robinson, Joan, economist, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Rockefeller, Nelson, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 30, Box 7, Folder 3)
- Rogers, Ginger, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Rose, Lucille, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Rossner, Judith, author, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Roy, Julie (photo only), undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Runyon, Marie (photo only), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Ryan, Aileen (photo only), undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Sand, George (photo only), undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Sanford, Terry (photo only), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Santaella, Irma Vidal, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 26, Box 7, Folder 3)
- Sappho, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Sassower, Doris L. (attorney), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Saxe: new material - articles, letters, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Saxe, Susan - article, letters, statements of support, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 3, Folder 29, Box 7, Folder 6, Box 8, Folder 4)
- Saxe, Susan and Power, Katherine Anne: Contempt Charges - articles, letters, personal statements, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14, Box 8, Folder 1)
- Saxe-Power: Boston, MA - article, note, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Saxe-Power: Cincinnati, OH - notes, letters, articles, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Saxe-Power: Hartford, CT - letters, article, info, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Saxe-Power: Lexington, KY - articles, letters, notes, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Box 8, Folder 4)
- Saxe-Power: New Britain, CT: - notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Saxe-Power: New Haven, CT - letters, articles, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 43, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Saxe-Power: New York, NY - article, photo, statement, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Saxe-Power: Philadelphia, PA - letters, articles, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Saxe-Power, San Francisco, CA - article, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Schiff, Dorothy, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Scully, Sister Jane, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Seaman, Barbara, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Seton, Mother Elizabeth, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Shakur, Assata (Joanne, Chesimard) - articles, statement, bulletins, newspaper, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15-16, Box 8, Folder 5)
- Shalala, Donna, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Shapp, Milton (Governor of Pennsylvania), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Shriver, Eunice, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Siegel, Jean, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Siegel, Mark Alan - campaign pamphlet, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Silkwood, Karen - photo, articles, newsletter, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Sloan, Margaret - photo, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Smeal, Eleanor - letter, article, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Smith, Margaret Chase - photo reprint, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Smith, Patty - articles, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19, Box 8, Folder 1)
- Solanas, Valerie - letters, article, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Spock, Dr. Benjamin - article, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 21, Box 8, Folder 1)
- Steinem, Gloria - photos, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Stern, Susan - obituary, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Susann, Jacqueline - article, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Sutton, Percy E. - newsletters, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Swann, Marjorie - article, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Swinton, Pat - articles, 1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 36, Box 8, Folder 1)
- Tennov, Dorothy, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Tobias, Sheila - photo, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Ullmann, Liv - A Doll's House photos, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Vida, Ginny, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Wanrow, Yvonne - pamphlet, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Warden, Kay - article, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Welch, Raquel - article, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Williams, Cindy - article, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Williams, Dell - statement, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Wilson, Katherine - article, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Woods, Rose Mary - cartoon, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Woolf, Virginia - article, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Youngstein, Fran - articles, photos, releases, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 23, Box 8, Folder 1)